A Guide to the Eleanor P. Sheppard Papers 1924-1978
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
Eleanor P. Sheppard Papers 1924-1978
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 277
16 linear feet
Eleanor P. Sheppard
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated to the Department by Mrs. Sheppard on 17 April 1990.
Biographical/Historical Information
A native of Pelham, Georgia, Eleanor Parker attended Limestone College. She married Thomas E. Sheppard in 1928 and lived in Georgia and Arizona before moving to Richmond in 1936. Mrs. Sheppard began her political career through her activities with the Ginter PArk PTA. In 1954, when she was president of the Richmond Federation of PTAs and a member of the Council of Women's Organiziations, she ran for City Council. She served on the Richmond City Council from 1954 until 1968. During her tenure on council she became Richmond's first woman vice mayor (1960-1962) and later mayor (1962-1964). She left council in 1968 run for the Virginia House of Delegates, where she represented Richmond until March 1977. Mrs. Sheppard became the first chairwoman of a Virginia General Assembly committee in 1974 when she assumed the leadership of the House Education Committee. She also served on the Finance and Health, Welfare and Institutions committees.
Mrs. Sheppard was honored by numerous groups toward the end of her active career for her many contributions to the community. She died 14 March 1991 after a long illness.
Scope and Content Information
The collection covers Mrs. Sheppard's civic and political career from the mid 1950s until 1978. The issues covered include education, city planning and development and various bills proposed in the General Assembly. Materials include correspondence, reports, speeches, campaign documents, statements, photographs, publications and a vast quantity of newspaper clippings (to be indexed). Photographs have been transferred to RG 60, Box. The collection was very disorganized when received and the order described below was established by the Department. The collection originally contained a vast number of name tags, buttons, business cards and souvenirs. All but representative samples have been disposed of.
Arrangement
Arrangement
Collection is arranged alphabetically.
Organization
Series I--Personal and Civic materials (n.d., 1954-1970)
Series II--City Council (n.d., 1924-1968)
General Assembly (n.d., 1967-1978)
Series IV--Oversize materials (n.d., 1954- 1975 from series I and II)
Series V--Programs and Publications.
Contents List
- Series I-Personal and Civic materials, n.d. 1954-1970
  - 5000 Days in Richmond, n.d. (Box-folder 1.1)
  - Arts, n.d. 1954-1955, 1957-1958, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 1.2)
  - Awards, n.d. 1965 (Box-folder 1.3)
  - Central Richmond Association, n.d. 1970 (Box-folder 1.4)
  - Children's Theater 1962-1963 (Box-folder 1.5)
  - Christmas Pageant 1969 (Box-folder 1.6)
  - Correspondence: Christmas Mother 1953-1954 (Box-folder 1.7)
  - Correspondence: Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Junior League of Richmond, n.d. (Box-folder 1.9)
  - People: Biographies (Box-folder 1.10)
    Elizabeth
    Bernard, Louise
    Bliley, Thomas J., Jr.
    Bliss, Mrs. Terry
    Brawley, Eleanor
    Brothers, J. David
    Bryan, D. Tennant
    Cardwell, Charles P., Jr.
    Cephas, B. Addison, Jr.
    Crandall, Dr. Paul
    Crater, Flora
    Crowe, Merrill M.
    Daniel, William V.
    Du Val, Chalkley
    Emroughty, J.M.
    Forb, Nathan J.
    Gillespie, J. Samuel, Jr.
    Gold, Rev. William
    Graham, Arthur
    Grey, Robert J.
    Grimsley, James
    Hancock, Coalter Cabell
    Harns, Burt I.
    Harrison, Arthur
    Hechler, Katheryne
    James, Mrs. Allix
    Johnson, Julius R.
    Johnston, J. Ambler
    Kilgore, Ann
    Kittenplan, Mrs. Philip
    Lasday, Mrs. Albert
    Lawrence, Eleanor A.
    Mackenzie, Ross
    Madden, John B.
    Marshall, George C.
    Maxwell, Sarah
    McNamara, T.R.
    Meacham, Harry M.
    Mebane, R. Alan
    Meir, Golda
    Moody, George
    Moore, Hullihen, W.
    Morris, Philip
    Newman, Mrs. Cynthia
    Nichols,Walter
    Orndoff, J.M.,Jr.
    Pollard, Jane DeJarnette
    Rennie, Wayland W.
    Rhee, Syngman Robertson, William B.
    Robins, Claiborne
    Rountrey, James
    Satterfield, Blanche
    Scott, Mrs. Marion
    Shackleford, Lorraine M.
    Simons, Helen Stone, Mara
    Stratton, John
    Strauss, Lewis
    Thompson, Aubrey H.
    Thompson, William M., Jr.
    Valentine, Henry L.
    Wayne, Edward A.
    Wheat, James C.
    White, Rebecca Clark
    Willett, Henry I.
    Wood, Mary Elizabeth
- Series II-City Council, n.d. 1924-1968
  - Correspondence 1954 (Box-folder 1.11)
  - Correspondence 1955-1961 (Box-folder 1.12)
  - Correspondence, January-September 1962 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Correspondence, October-December 1962 (Box-folder 1.14)
  - Correspondence 1963 (Box-folder 2.1)
  - Correspondence, January-March 1964 (Box-folder 2.2)
  - Correspondence, April-May 1964 (Box-folder 2.3)
  - Correspondence, June-August 1964 (Box-folder 2.4)
  - Correspondence, September-December 1964 (Box-folder 2.5)
  - Correspondence 1965 (Box-folder 2.6)
  - Correspondence, January-March 1966 (Box-folder 3.1)
  - Correspondence, June-December 1966 (Box-folder 3.2)
  - Education, n.d. 1959, 1963-1966, 1968 (Box-folder 3.3)
  - Education: Articles, Notes and clippings (Box-folder 3.4)
  - Education: Improving Human Resources through Education 1962 (Box-folder 3.5)
  - Education: Richmond Public Schools, n.d. 1957-1959, 1962, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 3.6)
  - Education: Rules and Regulations of the School Board 1963 (Box-folder 3.7)
  - Education: School Board Budget 1963 (Box-folder 3.8)
  - Education: School Board Budget 1964-1965 (Box-folder 3.9)
  - Education: School Board Budget 1965-1966 (Box-folder 3.10)
  - Education: Vocational and Adult Education, n.d. 1952-1954, 1956, 1963 (Box-folder 3.11)
  - League of Virginia Municipalities 1954 (Box-folder 4.1)
  - Press Releases and Coverage, n.d. 1956, 1962-1963, 1965-1971 (Box-folder 4.1a)
  - Report and Recommendations on Coliseum Management 1967 (Box-folder 4.2)
  - Report of a Survey: Bureau of Police 1955 (Box-folder 4.3)
  - Report on Broad Street Methodist Church 1966 (Box-folder 4.4)
  - Report on Bureau of Police 1960 (Box-folder 4.5)
  - Report on Bureau Police v. I 1960 (Box-folder 4.6)
  - Report on Bureau of Police v. III, n.d. 1960 (Box-folder 4.7)
  - Report on Bureau of Police (Confidential) 1960 (Box-folder 4.8)
  - Report on Criminal Activity 1967 (Box-folder 4.9)
  - Report on Cultural Center 1962 (Box-folder 4.10)
  - Report on Education in Richmond Public Schools 1954 (Box-folder 5.1)
  - Report on Examination of Records 1960 (Box-folder 5.2)
  - Report on Festival of Arts (11th Annual) 1967 (Box-folder 5.3)
  - Report on Richmond Nursing Home 1967 (Box-folder 5.4)
  - Report on Shoplifting 1967 (Box-folder 5.5)
  - Richmond City Chamber of Commerce 1964 (Box-folder 5.6)
  - Richmond City Council 1960-1968 (Box-folder 5.7)
  - Richmond City Council: Arts 1963 (Box-folder 5.8)
  - Richmond City Council: Belvidere Extension 1954-1956 (Box-folder 5.9)
  - Richmond City Council: Belvidere Underpass, n.d. (Box-folder 5.10)
  - Richmond City Council: Bonds 1954-1963-1964 (Box-folder 5.11)
  - Richmond City Council: Budget 1955-1968 (Box-folder 5.12)
  - Richmond City Council: Housing 1967 (Box-folder 5.13)
  - Richmond City Council: Jail, n.d. 1956-1958, 1967 (Box-folder 5.14)
  - Richmond City Council: Legislative Committee 1965-1966 (Box-folder 5.15)
  - Richmond City Council: Members (Box-folder 6.1)
  - Richmond City Council: Milk Dating, n.d. 1957-1958 (Box-folder 6.2)
  - Richmond City Council: Mosque 1967 (Box-folder 6.3)
  - Richmond City Council: NAACP, n.d. 1963 (Box-folder 6.4)
  - Richmond City Council: Parking 1957-1960 (Box-folder 6.5)
  - Richmond City Council: Personnel, n.d. (Box-folder 6.6)
    1954-1955, 1957-1958, 1960, 1963-1965, 1967
  - Richmond City Council: Pine Camp 1957-1958 (Box-folder 6.7)
  - Richmond City Council: Pool Site 1966 (Box-folder 6.8)
  - Richmond City Council: Real Estate Tax 1954, 1958-1959, 1961, 1964 (Box-folder 6.9)
  - Richmond City Council: Resolutions 1964-1967 (Box-folder 6.10)
  - Richmond City Council: Richmond Public Library, n.d. (Box-folder 6.11)
    1924, 1929, 1954-1961, 1967
  - Richmond City Council: Richmond Tour 1965-1966 (Box-folder 6.12)
  - Richmond City Council: Sales Tax 1962 (Box-folder 6.13)
  - Richmond City Council: Task Force on Poverty, n.d. (Box-folder 6.14)
  - Richmond City Council: Taxes 1958-1964 (Box-folder 7.1)
  - Richmond City Planning and Housing 1955-1967
  - Richmond City Planning Commission, July-August 1964-1965 (Box-folder 7.3)
  - Richmond City Planning Commission 1965-1966 (Box-folder 7.4)
  - Richmond City Planning Commission: Committee on Office Administration and Proceedings 1965-1966 (Box-folder 7.5)
  - Richmond City Planning Commission: Master Plan 1964 (Box-folder 7.6)
  - Richmond City Planning Commission: Monument Avenue 1965-1966 (Box-folder 8.1)
  - Richmond City Planning Commission: Mosque 1959-1966 (Box-folder 8.2)
  - Richmond City Planning Commission: Mosque Report 1965 (Box-folder 8.3)
  - Richmond City Planning Commission: Parking Plan for Civic Center 1960 (Box-folder 8.4)
  - Richmond City Planning Commission: Preliminary Study Proposed Coliseum 1964 (Box-folder 8.5)
  - Richmond City Planning Commission: Proposal for Richmond Civic Center 1963, 1965 (Box-folder 8.6)
  - Richmond City Planning Commission: Richmond Coliseum 1962-1966 (Box-folder 8.7)
  - Richmond City Planning Commission: Report on Organization Procedure and Program 1966 (Box-folder 8.8)
  - Richmond City Planning Commission: Report on Organization Procedure and program (Final) 1967 (Box-folder 9.1)
  - Richmond City Planning Commission: Study of Economic Feasibility of Coliseum 1966 (Box-folder 9.2)
  - Richmond Metropolitan Authority Expressway 1967 (Box-folder 9.3)
  - Richmond Metropolitan Authority Expressway System: Engineering Report 1966 (Box-folder 9.4)
  - Richmond Forward 9.5 (Box-folder 9.5)
  - Richmond Public Schools, n.d. (Box-folder 9.6)
  - Richmond Regional Development Plan 1967 (Box-folder 9.7)
  - RPI-MCV Merger 1966-1967 (Box-folder 9.8)
  - Road Study, n.d. (Box-folder 9.9)
  - Sears, Roebuck and Co. 1971 (Box-folder 9.10)
  - Special Committee in Annexation and Consolidation 1963 (Box-folder 9.11)
  - Speeches and Scripts (Box-folder 10.1)
  - Stationery (Box-folder 10.2)
  - Study on Charter Changes 1963 (Box-folder 10.3)
  - Sutton, T. Dix (Dunn-Ball-Carwile) (Box-folder 10.4)
  - Tax Revisions 1955-1965 (Box-folder 10.5)
  - Tax Studies and Reports 1960-1961, 1967 (Box-folder 10.6)
  - Tickets, Passes, n.d. 1962-1967 (Box-folder 10.7)
  - Tobacco Festival Grand Ball: Questionnaire for Hostesses 1969 (Box-folder 10.8)
  - Virginia Council on Human Relations 1964 (Box-folder 11.1)
  - Virginia Federation of Democratic Women's Clubs 1968-1972 (Box-folder 11.2)
  - Voting 1964-1971 (Box-folder 11.3)
  - Westwood Survey 1968 (Box-folder 11.4)
- Series III-General Assembly, n.d. 1967-1978
  - Articulation-Transfer of credit within state supported universities and colleges 1975-1977 (Box-folder 11.41)
  - Bills and Drafts 1973-1977 (Box-folder 11.42)
  - Charter Bills 1968-1969, 1973 (Box-folder 11.43)
  - Clippings re: Handicapped, n.d. (Box-folder 11.44)
    1964, 1966, 1968, 1970-1971, 1974-1977
  - Collective Bargaining (Box-folder 11.45)
  - College Tuition, n.d. 1975-1977 (Box-folder 12.0)
  - Commission on State Governmental Management-Information Papers on the Agencies of State Government 1976 (Box-folder 12.1)
  - Commission on State Governmental Management-Report and Correspondence 1976 (Box-folder 12.2)
  - Commission Report re: Problems of Richmond's Boundary Expansion 1969 (Box-folder 12.3)
  - Committee on Education and Labor Hearings 1977 (Box-folder 12.4)
  - Community Colleges 1975-1977 (Box-folder 12.5)
  - Community Development 1968 (Box-folder 13.0)
  - Competency Testing 1976-1977 (Box-folder 13.1)
  - Congratulations 1971 (Box-folder 13.2)
  - Congressional Bills 1977 (Box-folder 13.3)
  - Congressional Delegation, n.d. 1968, 1970 (Box-folder 13.4)
  - Controversy 1973-1974, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 13.5)
  - Correspondence, January-June 1967 (Box-folder 13.6)
  - Correspondence, August-December 1967 (Box-folder 13.7)
  - Correspondence, July 1967 (Box-folder 13.8)
  - Correspondence 1968 (Box-folder 13.9)
  - Correspondence 1969 (Box-folder 14.1)
  - Correspondence 1970-1972 (Box-folder 14.2)
  - Correspondence, January 1973 (Box-folder 14.3)
  - Correspondence, February 1973 (Box-folder 14.4)
  - Correspondence, March 1973, 1975 (Box-folder 14.5)
  - Division for Children-Extended Day Care Task Force 1978-1980 (Box-folder 14.6)
  - Divorce, n.d. 1972, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 15.0)
  - Economic Value of the Housewife, n.d. 1973, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 15.1)
  - Education 1978 (Box-folder 15.2)
  - Education-Title IX 1976 (Box-folder 15.3)
  - Education Commission of the States 1977-1978 (Box-folder 15.4)
  - ECS-Affirmative Action 1975-1977 (Box-folder 15.4a)
  - ECS Bulletin 1975 (Box-folder 15.5)
  - ECS Commission Handbook 1974 (Box-folder 15.6)
  - ECS Commissioner Handbook 1978 (Box-folder 15.7)
  - ECS Commissioner Newsletter 1976-1977 (Box-folder 15.8)
  - ECS Correspondence 1973-1976 (Box-folder 15.9)
  - ECS Correspondence, Newsletters, Pamphlets, etc. 1976-1978 (Box-folder 15.9a)
  - ECS Early Childhood Project Newsletter 1975-1977 (Box-folder 15.9b)
  - ECS Education for Handicapped Children, n.d. 1976-1977 (Box-folder 16.1)
  - ECS Financing Ed. Programs for Handicapped Children 1972, 1974 (Box-folder 16.2)
  - ECS Handicapped Child Ed. Proj. 1975 (Box-folder 16.3)
  - ECS Higher Education in the States Newsletter 1975-1977 (Box-folder 16.4)
  - ECS Legislative Review 1977-1978 (Box-folder 16.4a)
  - ECS Meeting, Bloomington, MN June 27-29, 1973 (Box-folder 16.5)
  - ECS Meeting, Doral, Florida 1974 (Box-folder 16.6)
  - ECS Meeting, Kansas City, Mo June 19-July 2, 1975 (Box-folder 16.7)
  - ECS Meeting, San Francisco, Ca. May 26-28, 1976 (Box-folder 17.1)
  - ECS Meeting, New York, NY June 14-17, 1977 (Box-folder 17.2)
  - ECS News Releases, n.d. 1975 (Box-folder 17.3)
  - ECS Policy Positions 1965-1977 (Box-folder 17.4)
  - ECS State Postesecondary Edu. Profiles Handbook 1976 (Box-folder 17.5)
  - Education Committee Study on Schools for the Blind and Deaf, n.d. 1975-1976 (Box-folder 17.6)
  - Education of Handicapped/LD Children, n.d. 1973 (Box-folder 18.0)
  - Election 1969 (Box-folder 18.1)
  - Election 1975 (Box-folder 18.2)
  - Election: Advertising for Governor 1971 (Box-folder 18.3)
  - Election: Assistance 1973 (Box-folder 18.4)
  - Election: Campaign Headquarters 1967 (Box-folder 18.5)
  - Election: City Democratic Committee (Box-folder 18.6)
  - Election: Crusade for Voters, n.d. 1965-1971, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 18.7)
  - Election: Democratic Primary 1971 (Box-folder 18.8)
  - Election: Democratic Primary--Finance 1967 (Box-folder 18.8(1))
  - Election: Democrats 1975 (Box-folder 18.8(2))
  - Election: Democrats--State and U.S., n.d. 1965-1971 (Box-folder 18.8(3))
  - Election: General Assembly 1975 (Box-folder 19.0)
  - Election: Laws 19.1 (Box-folder 19.1)
  - Election: Miscellaneous (Box-folder 19.2)
  - Finance Reports 1971 (Box-folder 19.3)
  - Finance-Special Education, n.d. 1974-1977 (Box-folder 19.4)
  - General Assembly: Bills 1964, 1968 (Box-folder 19.5)
  - General Assembly: Resolutions, n.d. (Box -19.6)
  - Governmental Change 1976-1977 (Box-folder 19.7)
  - Governmental Reorganization 1970, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 19.8)
  - Governor's Committee and Advisory Council on Handicapped Education, n.d. 1975-1976 (Box-folder 20.1)
  - Handicapped Bills, etc., n.d. 1975-1977 (Box-folder 20.2)
  - Handicapped Education-IEP, n.d. 1972, 1977 (Box-folder 20.3)
  - Handicapped Subcommittee Minutes 1977 (Box-folder 20.4)
  - Handicapped Publications and Papers, n.d. 1972-1975 (Box-folder 20.5)
  - Handicapped Publications and Papers 1976 (Box-folder 20.6)
  - Handicapped Publications and Papers 1977 (Box-folder 20.7)
  - HB 547 Student Activity Fee, n.d. 1975-1977 (Box-folder 21.0)
  - HB 692 School of Law at George Mason University 1973-1977 (Box-folder 21.1)
  - HB 1057 Tuition for Handicapped Children, n.d. 1974, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 21.2)
  - HB 1106 Higher Education Consortia 1974-1976 (Box-folder 21.3)
  - Health Education 1976-1977 (Box-folder 21.4)
  - Health Education Advisory Committee, n.d. 1973, 1975, 1977 (Box-folder 21.5)
  - Higher Education Letters, n.d. 1975-1977 (Box-folder 21.6)
  - Higher Education Newspaper Articles, n.d. 1970-1977 (Box-folder 21.7)
  - House of Delegates 1967-1968, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 21.8)
  - House of Delegates, Misc., n.d. 1963-1969, 1971-1977 (Box-folder 21.9)
  - Inheritance and Gift Taxes, n.d. 1975-1977 (Box-folder 21.9(1))
  - James Madison University, n.d. 1976-1977 (Box-folder 21.9(2))
  - James River History: Proposals re: Enhancement: Locks, n.d. 1954, 1957, 1962-1973 (Box-folder 21.9(3))
  - Joint Commemorative Session of General Assembly 1968 (Box-folder 22.1)
  - Joint Ownership Between Spouses, n.d. 1977 (Box-folder 22.2)
  - Kindergarten and Early Childhood Education, n.d. 1964, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 22.3)
  - Law-Related Education Advisory Committee 1972, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 22.4)
  - Legislative Platforms, n.d. 1968-1973 (Box-folder 22.5)
  - Letters and Statements 1962, 1971 (Box-folder 22.6)
  - Letters on Handicapped, n.d. 1972-1977 (Box-folder 22.7)
  - Mainstreaming-Technical Assistance Program, n.d. 1975 (Box-folder 22.8)
  - Maymont: Proposal for Development 1971 (Box-folder 22.9)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box-folder 22.9(1))
    1955-1959, 1962-1969, 1971, 1973-1974, 1976-1978
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. 1972-1976 (Box-folder 22.9(2))
  - National Assessment of Educational Progress (NAEP), n.d. 1975-1978 (Box-folder 23.0)
  - NAEP Brochures 1970-1975 (Box-folder 23.1)
  - NAEP Correspondence 1975-1976 (Box-folder 23.2)
  - NAEP Efficacy Report by Greenbaum 1974 (Box-folder 23.3)
  - NAEP Evaluation 1975 (Box-folder 23.4)
  - NAEP Greenbaum Report Reply: Goals and Accomplishments 1974-1975 (Box-folder 23.5)
  - NAEP Handbook 1977 (Box-folder 23.6)
  - NAEP Minutes 1974-1978 (Box-folder 23.7)
  - NAEP Newsletter 1975-1978 (Box-folder 23.8)
  - NAEP Organization, n.d. 1975-1976 (Box-folder 23.9)
  - NAEP Procedures, n.d. 1974-1978 (Box-folder 23.9(1))
  - NAEP Reports 1973-1975 (Box-folder 24.0)
  - NAEP Reports 1975-1977 (Box-folder 24.1)
  - NAEP Reports 1977-1978 (Box-folder 24.2)
  - NAEP State and Local School District Services 1976-1977 (Box-folder 24.3)
  - NAEP Sucontracting 1975 (Box-folder 24.4)
  - NAEP Utilization, n.d. 1975-1976 (Box-folder 24.5)
  - National Assn. for Retarded Citizens (NARC) Statements, n.d. 1971, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 25.0)
  - National Center for Educational Statistic-National Assessment Information 1976 (Box-folder 25.1)
  - National Committee on Uniform Traffic Laws and Ordinances-Agenda for the Subcommittee on Scope, Jurisdiction and Enforcement 1978 (Box-folder 25.2)
  - National Conference of State Legislatures 1975-1977 (Box-folder 25.3)
  - Optometry Schools 1976-1977 (Box-folder 25.4)
  - Postsecondary Education Policy Development in Four State Legislatures 1975 (Box-folder 25.5)
  - Precinct Organization: General, n.d. (Box-folder 25.6)
  - Press Releases and coverage (Box-folder 25.7)
  - Primary: Finance 1969 (Box-folder 25.8)
  - Primary: Organization 1969 (Box-folder 25.8(1))
  - Program Evaluation of Community College System-Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission 1975 (Box-folder 25.9)
  - Public Law 94-142 1974, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 26.0)
  - Public Law 94-142 and Handicapped Student Rights 1975-1977 (Box-folder 26.1)
  - Questions and Answers (Box-folder 26.2)
  - R-CAP Study Committee Report 1970 (Box-folder 26.3)
  - Report on National Assessment of Educational Progress 1976 (Box-folder 26.4)
  - Republicans 1969 (Box-folder 26.5)
  - Resource Material 1967-1970 (Box-folder 26.6)
  - Retirement-Supplemental for State Employees 1969, 1976 (Box-folder 26.7)
  - Richmond-Counties-Annexation-Charters_HAHN Commission-General, n.d. 1966-1971, 1980 (Box-folder 26.8)
  - Richmond Area Community Council Membership Meetings Newsletter 1969-1973 (Box-folder 27.0)
  - Richmond Public Schools, n.d. 1974, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 27.1)
  - Rights of Spouses, n.d. 1974-1978 (Box-folder 27.2)
  - Salaries of School Board Members 1976-1977 (Box-folder 27.3)
  - School Board Selection 1969-1970, 1977 (Box-folder 27.4)
  - School Division Criteria Study Commission, n.d. 1969, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 27.5)
  - School Personnel-Employment and Certification 1975-1977 (Box-folder 27.6)
  - Souther Regional Education Legislation by States: Southern Regional Education Board 1974-1978 (Box-folder 27.7)
  - Southern Regional Education Legislation Workshop Biloxi 1975 (Box-folder 27.7(1))
  - Southern Regional Education Legislation Workshop 1976 (Box-folder 27.7(2))
  - Southern Regional Education Publications (Box-folder 27.7(3))
  - Special Education-Amended Annual Program Plan FY 1976 (Box-folder 28.0)
  - Special Education-Standards of Quality, n.d. 1972-1977 (Box-folder 28.0(1))
  - State Council for Higher Education, n.d. 1974-1977 (Box-folder 28.1)
  - State Department of Education-Handicapped 1976-1977 (Box-folder 28.2)
  - Statements 1967-1971 (Box-folder 28.3)
  - Subcommittee on School Lunches, n.d. 1977 (Box-folder 28.4)
  - Tenure-State Supported Colleges and Universities, n.d. 1973, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 28.5)
  - Title I 1973-1974 (Box-folder 28.6)
  - University Faculty Tenure, n.d. 1968, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 28.7)
  - University of Virginia Newsletter 1960, 1965, 1968-1969, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 28.8)
  - Veterinary Schools, n.d. 1974-1977 (Box-folder 28.9)
  - Virginia Assn. for Children with Learning Disabilities (VACLD) Newsletter 1973-1977 (Box-folder 29.0)
  - Virginia Constitutional Revision 1969 (Box-folder 29.0(1))
  - Virginia Council of Administrators of Special Education 1974-1976 (Box-folder 29.1)
  - Virginia Education Association 1976-1977 (Box-folder 29.2)
  - Virginia School Boards Assn. 1975-1978 (Box-folder 29.3)
  - Virginia Special Education Legislation, n.d. 1974, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 29.4)
  - VPI_SU Library, n.d. 1977 (Box-folder 29.5)
  - William and Mary Law School 1974-1977 (Box-folder 29.6)
  - Will, n.d. 1972, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 29.7)
  - Women's Finances, n.d. 1975-1978 (Box-folder 29.8)
  - Youth Commission and Related Items, n.d. 1976-1977 (Box-folder 29.9)
  - Youth Commission and Related Items II, n.d. 1970, 1975, 1977 (Box-folder 29.9(1))
- Series IV-Oversize, n.d. 1954-1975
  - Election Campaign 1967-1969 (Box-folder 30.1)
  - Election: Council 1954, 1958-1966 (Box-folder 30.2)
  - Richmond City Council: Southside Community Center 1963 (Box-folder 30.3)
  - Precinct Reports 1975 (Box-folder 30.4)
  - Virginia Municipal League: Legislative Support Committee 1963-1964 (Box-folder 30.5)
  - American Heart Association/Virginia Affiliate 1977-1978, oversize (Box 31)
  - American Municipal Association 1963, oversize (Box 31)
  - Annual Reports Various Organizations 1954-1973, oversize (Box 31)
  - Application for Legislative Assistant 1974, oversize (Box 31)
  - Assembly Business 1970-1977, oversize (Box 31)
  - Association for the Preservation of Virginia Antiquities 1961-1977, oversize (Box 31)
  - Brookings Institute-U.R. Seminar 1964-1965 (Box 31)
  - Buford Academy 1956-1966, oversize (Box 31)